SUSEENDHAR LAL

Software Engineer

Hello, I'm a Full Stack Developer with more than 2 years of experience in Web development. I Love Creating High Quality Websites And Apps That Use The Latest And Greatest Tools Out There To Maximize UI And UX Quality. I enjoy the process of making a web site/app from start to finish.



- Chennai, India
- suseendhar.netlify.app
- github.com/suseendharlal96

- +91-8012543335/+91-7904217073
- # 08 August, 1996
- in linkedin.com/in/suseendhar-lal-312709155

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software EngineerObject Frontier Software

03/2020 - Present

Work Order Management

My responsibility:

- As a team of 3 members, I take the responsibility of developing websites from the given UX.
- React along with redux is used for the UI part.
- NodeJs is used for creating RESTful Api's and sending the response JSON.

Junior Software EngineerObject Frontier Software

03/2019 - Present

Project Mangement System

My responsibility:

- As a full stack developer, created sites using React and also did an important role in creating REST API's using Nodejs and storing data on mongodb.
- Responsible for creating re-usable and flexible components using React and managing store using Redux.

Software Engineer traineeObject Frontier Software

09/2018 - 03/2019

Chennai

Chennai

Chennai

Achievements/Tasks

 Got trained as a software engineer and most predominantly on the user interface and frameworks like Reactjs.

CERTIFICATES

Reactis(beginner to advanced) by Udemy

Vueis by Udemy

HTML5 and CSS3 by Udemy

Introduction to programming using Javascript by sololearn

Machine Learning by coursera

EDUCATION

BE Computer ScienceRajalakshmi Engineering College

SKILLS

HTML CSS/SCSS JS ReactJs/Redux

Nodejs MongoDB GraphQL NextJs

GatsbyJs VueJs/Vuex GIT VSCode

NoSQL Headless CMS Firebase

PERSONAL WORKS

https://suseendhar.netlify.app/projects

ACCOLADES

Camlin District Level

Camlin

Bagged the first prize at Camlin District Level art competition.

Velammal science talent exam

Velammal

Gold medalist.

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Limited Working Proficiency

Tamil

Full Professional Proficiency

Sourashtra

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Listening to music

Watching movies

Working on Mini projects